Extreme justice is extreme injustice.
Cicero, "On Moral Duties"
What happens now?
This supplementary exam was clearly a pretext
designed to get rid of you.
But settling things between us
that way wouldn't be any fun.
That is why I decided to use
Class A's positive votes to protect you.
Why Yamauchi?
Do you recall his rude behavior
during the training camp?
It was payback for that.
Oh, hello.
I'm the school's new acting chairman.
My name is Tsukishiro.
3rd Season
Classroom
of
the
Elite
Classroom of
the Elite
Tsukishiro?
It's my first time here at the school.
Which way to the teachers' office?
Our new acting chairman has a
terrible sense of direction, I see.
And here I thought you'd spotted
us on the surveillance cameras
and came to meet us.
What an amusing theory.
The building that houses
the teachers' office is—
From the rumors, I expected more
from you, Ayanokoji Kiyotaka-kun.
That was quite aggressive of you.
Weren't you the one issuing
orders to get him expelled?
Since the school's top brass
refuses to openly expel someone,
it's understandable that you'd want
to act through someone like me.
But don't you think
our acting chairman resorting to
open assault might cause problems?
Not at all.
I've swapped a dummy video
into the security camera.
A message from your father.
"I refuse to play along with
these childish games any longer.
Return at once."
If your answer is yes, blink twice.
No intention to voluntarily leave school?
My position at this school will
be official beginning in April.
Look forward to it.
Not fighting back was a wise choice.
You never know how the footage might be used.
More importantly, Sakayanagi...
Would you like to officially
compete on the upcoming exam?
I wasn't expecting you to
be the one to propose it.
If he's going to start meddling in April,
I'd like to make our standing
clear and be done with it first.
Yes. I'll gladly face you.
I will now explain the final
special exam of this school year.
Your combined might will be
put to the test in an exam
based off of subjects of your choice.
As in the paper shuffle,
you'll face off against another class.
First, you'll choose any ten
subjects you like for the exam.
If there are any questions,
feel free to ask, Ike.
B-But...
You're not gonna get mad
at me for interrupting?
I start to get nervous if I don't hear
one of your pointless interruptions.
Then... could it be
rock-paper-scissors or something?
No way, man!
Let's assume rock-paper-scissors
is one of them.
Seriously?!
Of course.
The only points of caution:
No duplicated subjects.
No subjects that might present
difficulties with facilities,
seasons, or number of people.
Nothing too obscure.
Beer Pong
Roundnet
Kronum
Padel
Hurling
Dacau
Jai Alai
Wood Cobra
Academic subjects must be
part of the curriculum,
Language Math English Social Studies
History Biology Chemistry Physics
and the school will write the questions.
You're free to decide the rules yourselves,
but they must not allow for ties.
Your opposing class will
also submit ten subjects
for a total of twenty subjects.
We're doing twenty subjects?!
That's way too many!
No.
On the day of the test, each class will
choose five subjects out of the ten offered.
So the other five are like a bluff?
Yes.
The actual test will consist
of seven subjects.
The school will choose one
at random for each round.
You won't be told what the next subject is,
and once a student has participated,
they can't participate
again until everyone has.
My head is spinning with
all this information...
So... that means...
Out of all the subjects
we submit to each other,
we only compete in seven of them.
Oh, okay.
And the most important rule
is the existence of a team captain.
The student chosen as captain can't
participate in any of the subjects,
but they can be involved in all subjects,
and will receive bonus
points if their class wins.
And if their class loses?
The captain will be expelled immediately.
Not again!
After class, the captain will take part
in a lottery to pick your opponent.
You can select anyone you want.
Talk it out.
Final Special Exam Overview and Strategy Meeting
*These materials must be returned after the meeting.
Where'd Koenji go?
That bastard's messing around again!
Getting angry won't solve anything.
Hey, where'd Hirata-kun go?
I don't know.
He knew we were getting
together after class...
Hirata-kun remains useless,
so I suppose I'll have to do it myself.
I, um... I'm going to the bathroom!
I'll be back soon!
Hey.
There's one thing I wanna
get clear before we talk.
What is it?
There are a lot of people who don't
like how the last test turned out.
Right, Kanji?
I guess it's more like... I don't get it.
Why'd Ayanokoji place first in the vote?
Allow me to explain.
I have a theory.
Hold it.
We want the explanation from Ayanokoji.
Our buddy's gone, you know.
Sorry. I don't know, either.
Don't give me that crap!
I don't think Ayanokoji-kun knows the answer.
It was out of his control.
Out of his control?
What do you mean?
Remember what Yamauchi-kun said?
That's it. Sakayanagi!
Go talk to Sakayanagi!
She said she'd give me their positive votes!
How could she betray me like this?!
She made him think she'd
made a secret pact with him
to destroy Ayanokoji-kun, then betrayed him.
So why choose Ayanokoji?
He's a neutral entity.
The protection point will
be irrelevant with him.
I'm sure anyone else would
have worked just as well.
But... that's just you guessing!
That's right. It's an inference.
But if you want to be angry at someone,
be angry at me, not him.
I'm the primary reason
Yamauchi-kun was expelled.
Okay, but...
Is it okay if I volunteer to be
captain for this special exam?
It's true that I've lost
some of the class's trust.
Therefore, I want to clear the
suspicions by becoming a sacrifice.
Ayanokoji...
Sounds good to me!
Then no one'll have to be expelled!
Hey, hang on a minute.
That makes it sound like we're
going to throw the challenge.
Do we really want to fight some other
class under Ayanokoji-kun's leadership?
Shouldn't we consider other candidates?
I don't think anyone here wants
to run the risk of being expelled.
Myself included.
That's true, but...
And since he's got the protection point,
he's perfect for the job, right?
Even if he is the captain, others can
consult with him on planning beforehand.
It doesn't particularly
matter who plays the role.
Horikita's pushing hard for
me in the captain role.
And I doubt anyone will object.
Are there any objections?
Will you take it on, then, Ayanokoji-kun?
I will.
As expected, every class chose their
protection point holder as captain.
Starting with Class A,
each of you will draw one lot.
The class that draws the marked paper will
have the right to choose their opponent.
As they say, "Good things are found
in what others leave behind."
I shall draw last.
Please proceed, Ichinose-san.
Don't mind if I do!
Tokyo Metropolitan Advanced
Nurturing High School
Oh, too bad.
Tokyo Metropolitan Advanced
Nurturing High School
Acting Chairman
Tsukishiro
Right to Choose
Opposing Class
It's a winner.
It seems there's no need to check
the final paper, Mr. Mashima.
Right.
Kaneda, tell us which class you'd like to face.
Class D wants to face Class B.
Sounds good to me. No holding back, okay?
I had assumed you'd target Class C.
One route to a comeback would be to
go after the points of as
high a class as possible,
but I'd like to avoid facing Class A for now.
I see.
Best of luck to you.
This result was predetermined.
I arranged it with Ichinose
and Ishizaki in advance...
Ishizaki Daichi
Ayanokoji Kiyotaka
(No Subject)
Got it!
to make sure they'd let us fight Class A.
3rd Season
Classroom
of
the
Elite
Classroom of
the Elite
That's all for today.
It's over!
Hirata-kun!
Can I talk to you?
Could you please leave me alone?
But...
Just go away!
B-But I...
I'm just worried about you, so...
You have no reason to worry about me.
Hey, Yosuke-kun!
Don't you think that's going a little too far?
Don't call me by my given
name like we're friends.
We're not seeing each other anymore, right?
Fine, Hirata-kun.
You're being way too hard on Mii-chan.
I'm just acting how you usually do.
I-I'm doing it for the class!
Just shut up, would you?
If you don't...
You know what'll happen.
Wait, Hirata-kun!
No one can help Hirata-kun right now.
Focus on the conversation in front of you.
Surprised to see you stayed today, Koenji.
The Horikita girl practically begged me to.
That said, I hope today will
be the start and end of it.
I'm a busy man, you know.
I'll make it short, then.
Before the next class,
I want you all to submit a subject
you feel utmost confidence in.
I see.
"Now that you're in the discussion,
you'd better meet your quota," eh?
I'm sure you have at least one
especially strong subject.
Or will you willfully turn
the class against you?
Get it out of your head that
such words might sway me.
It's true that I'm an unparalleled genius,
but I'm the one who decides whether
or not I use that genius for you.
Unparalleled genius, my ass.
I'll speak with Koenji-kun later.
For now, let's see what happens.
Heya.
Rare for you to invite me to your place.
If anyone were to see us...
Um... wouldn't it be a problem?
It's growing less necessary that we hide.
Feels like our relationship is
becoming more and more open, huh?
Is that okay?
It's not an issue at all.
I want inside information on the class,
including what's going on with Hirata.
And we have to meet in person for that?
There are some things one can
best learn by meeting in person.
But first...
It's your birthday, isn't it?
You learned my birthday?
Hey, can I look inside?
Yes.
A necklace?!
And it's a heart?
Is this really a gift for a friend?
Wasn't it expensive?
It wasn't cheap. Approximately 20,000.
That's a lot!
It was number one on the site's list of
"best presents for high school girls."
I know you're smart,
but you're kinda dumb in that area.
Am I?
When you buy accessories for a girl,
you're supposed to pick them out yourself.
Honestly, this is pretty
much a 10 out of 100.
Would a box of cakes have been better?
That would've been a 15.
You got a mirror?
Do you think that I do?
I thought so.
A heart's a bit childish.
If you don't like it, you can leave it here.
But I'm gorgeous to start with, so pretty
much anything looks good on me.
I suppose I might as well keep it.
Feel free to, if you'd like.
Pedestrians and Bicycles Only
You're out early.
I had some business at the library.
Oh? Is the special exam proceeding well?
Your sister is certainly raring for a fight.
I see.
Regarding that, there's something
I've been wanting to ask you.
On the day we first met,
why did you chew her out
and try to drive her away?
I was disappointed in Suzune.
Not in her grades, but in her maturity.
Her maturity?
When she was a child,
she smiled a great deal.
But now she's dependent
on me. She imitates me.
And mimicking you is the reason
she plays the ice princess?
It's not just her attitude.
What she eats, drinks...
Even her favorite color and taste in clothing.
She's brought them all in line with mine.
That isn't growth.
So despite your flawless exterior,
you failed at properly
communicating with your sister?
There is no flawless human being. Is there?
I suppose not.
But she's trying to change now.
If Suzune were to stop chasing my phantom,
cut off her dependency,
and face herself with perfect honesty,
then she would surpass me, and become
someone that even you could not ignore.
But only if she's able to change.
I think she is changing.
No, that's not right.
I think I might try changing her.
Not in the gradual ways I've
done before, but genuinely.
Oh? Interesting to hear that from you.
I have one other question.
What is it?
Are you and Tachibana there dating?
No, not at all.
I see.
Still,
it's interesting to see such an ordinary
high school sentiment come from your mouth.
I believe I am an absolutely
ordinary high schooler.
Then, speaking as an ordinary high
schooler, have you found a girlfriend?
Not at the moment.
I wouldn't mind leaving Suzune in your hands,
but I can't quite see the
two of you together, either.
Of course you can't.
D-Don't say that!
You're gonna trigger a flag or something.
A flag?
Oh, um...
I mean, there's sort of a rule that
that kind of thing backfires.
It's pretty common to
see two people you think
would never get together start dating...
I-I mean, forget what I said.
There are too many tests!
Chess
Mental Math
Go
Modern Literature
Volleyball
Math
English
Jump Rope
Dodgeball
Class A really went for it...
These are the subjects submitted by Class A.
It'll be pretty hard to cover all this.
Yes.
But the same will be true for Class A.
The key will be figuring out which
subjects they're serious about.
Has anyone here ever played chess, even?
Chess...
Class A's Chosen Subjects
Game Rules and Rules for the Leader
・Chess
One player needed. Time allowance: one hour (absolute).
Rules: Standard chess rules, but more time is not granted after the 40th move.
Leader rules: The leader can give instructions to the player at his or her discretion
for, at most, 30 minutes of the allotted time.
・Mental Math
Two players needed. Time: 30 minutes.
Rules: Students compete for speed and accuracy in calculation using an abacus.
The class whose participant places first wins.
Leader rules: The leader may change one answer at his or her discretion.
・Go
Three players needed. Time allowance: one hour (absolute).
Rules: Three one-on-one matches will be conducted simultaneously.
Standard go rules...
In chess, the captain uses the allotted time
to give instructions to the players.
Which makes it possible
for two captains to duel.